<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Webfactories RSS]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is new description]]></description><link>https://webfactories.biz</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 08:22:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://webfactories.biz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Why making an eCommerce website is not just enough to survive the competition?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src='https://webfactories.biz/img/uploads/ecommerce-website-webposting.jpg' class='img-responsive'>

Every website, be it an eCommerce website or a normal blogging site, everyone needs to know what is happening around them so as to match pace in this competitive world.

Before we get into the deeper insights of how it works and which tools are required to make it work, we must first know what is the importance of it and how working on it can get us better returns. 

### Take a deep plunge

Your credibility as a web analyst depends on how deeper you can plunge into to get every minutest detail that has the potential to make a difference. As we know that our main aim or the target is to get traffic, so we can start with the categories of traffic which we have and they are as follows: 

<ul class="circle-list"><li>Direct</li><li>Campaign</li><li>Referral</li><li>Search </li></ul>

Direct traffic can be described as the one that comes from no source point or in short visitor had directly typed the Url of your website he read somewhere in passing or signboards.

Campaign traffic is the traffic received as a result of your marketing strategy. Referral traffic is the traffic received from the link submitted on different sites. Search traffic is the traffic received when people type their query in the search bars of search engines such as Google, Yahoo, MSN, Bing and others. 

For those who have a bit grasp on marketing might be aware of it.

Let's start with the analytics! 

### Integrate Google Analytics with your E-commerce website 

Google Analytics is by far one of the most standard tools when it comes to analyzing any traffic related activity on the web. These tools provide a comprehensive analysis and detailed reports that help you to get a cross-sectional view of what is happening in the market. Being a free tool, every business owner of scale can use this powerful analytical tool for their web store that pulls the data from the Google itself. All you need to do is to integrate it to your website, and this enables you to intertwine your sales to sessions that will connect the sales to all your marketing channels. 

To set up a Google Analytics, you need to go through a couple of steps, in which the first step is to go to your admin pannel of your eCommerce store and from there you need to incorporate eCommerce tracking. 

Then after, you need to make some alterations in the coding part as Google Analytics offers a piece of code using which the website is crawled via the web crawlers of the Google. For those who have no grasp of coding can take some help from the programmers.

### Analyze your Competition

**Alexa**

Alexa has outgrown all the other tools, being in the market since past 15 years.

The best part about this service is that it is mostly free and helps the user to analyze your contemporaries. No mathematics applied all you need is to type your URL of the firm, and you can get all the insights such as global rank, site links, audience insight, loading time of the site, search analytics, and many other competitive features.

Alexa gives you a very discursive analysis of the website, but you can find some discrepancies in the information delivered by the website. This is because they gather information from the one those who have installed their extension for Google Chrome or toolbar for Firefox or Internet Explorer.

### Social Media Analytics

Social media has undoubtedly become one of the most popular platforms for marketing your online stores. The best part about social media marketing is that you can chalk out a complete plan for your social media marketing strategy.

**Facebook Analytics Dashboard ** – Analytics of social media giant: Facebook- For those who have made a Facebook page might be aware of the Insights section offered by Facebook. 

Since its launch, we have seen numerous iterations of Facebook page insights. 

And the developers have come up with something new every time and have made the page quite friendly with each version.

**Twitter Analytics Dashboard** - Twitter, the micro blogging website has also grown luxuriantly and has become on of the most popular tool for disseminating your business via web and outreaching audiences. Though, it does not offer an analytics as Facebook does, but one can make use of Twitter Cards for doing so.

In order to make the best tweets ever, you can make use of tools like Sprout Social, Twtrland, or Hootsuite that help you to get analytics on impressions and traffic on your tweets.

### Effectively utilize this strategy

Now in order to get traffic on this website you need to make sure you go into deeper analytics and get to use it in the best possible way you can.

Now let us say that you have an eCommerce website selling apparels then you can use Facebook to reach your target audience. You can post your latest offers or discount coupons. Even you can post some of your ravishing offerings that are in vogue. You need to remember that when not manually tagged then a link is taken as referred traffic in Google Analytics and Facebook is taken as the referrer. Moreover, you can utilize each of the categories of the post for different marketing campaigns.

An effective planning will certainly help you to get Good returns!

<hr>

<strong>Author Signature:</strong> Maria Mincey is an web developer working with Xicom Technologies - <a href="http://www.xicom.biz/solutions/business/ecommerce.html" target="_blank">eCommerce web development company</a>. You can contact her in order to hire developers to avail the highly functional eCommerce and web development solutions. She has several years of experience in the field of web development.]]></description><link>https://webfactories.biz/posts/why-making-an-ecommerce-website-is-not-just-enough-to-survive-the-competition?</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://webfactories.biz/posts/why-making-an-ecommerce-website-is-not-just-enough-to-survive-the-competition?</guid><category><![CDATA[recent-blog]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://webfactories.biz/img/uploads/ecommerce-website-webposting.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Who needs a Wordpress Site]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src='https://webfactories.biz/img/uploads/who-needs-a-wordpress-site.jpg' class='img-responsive'>

A couple of years ago the answer was most likely everybody, now the answer is almost nobody. Why is that?

### When Static Was It

The first ever website, Tim Berners-Lee’s original home page for the World Wide Web, was static. A website back then was a folder of HTML documents that consisted of just 18 tags. Browsers were simple document navigators that would fetch HTML from a server and allow the end user to navigate them by following hyperlinks. The web was fundamentally static.

As browsers evolved, so did HTML, and gradually the limitations of purely static websites started to show.

The most mainstream answer to the limitations of Static Websites was the LAMP stack and CMS’ such as WordPress, Drupal and Joomla. All of these played an incredibly important role in moving the web forward, enabling the Web 2.0 phenomenon, in which user-generated content became a driving factor for a lot of websites. Users went from following hyperlinks to ordering products, participating in communities and creating content.

### Dynamic Website Wordpress Problems

The dynamic website architecture moved the web forward, but it also opened a can of worms. By a conservative estimate, more than 70% of today’s WordPress installations are vulnerable to known exploits (and WordPress powers more than 23% of the web). Just a few months ago, 12 million Drupal sites needed emergency patching, and any not patched within 7 hours of the exploits’ announcement should be considered infected with malware.. Not a week goes by when I don’t follow a link from social media to a website that shows a “Database connection error.” Scaling a dynamic website can be very expensive, and agencies that launch a campaign website or the like often have to overprovision drastically in order to guard against the website blowing up if it manages to go viral — or else they have to desperately scale it while trying to get it back online (something that never seems to happen during office hours).

We pay a huge price for the underlying complexity of dynamic code running on a server for every request — a price we could avoid paying entirely when this kind of complexity is not needed.

### Is Static the next big thing again and why now?

Why is static website technology taking off now, and why did the early generators fail to make a dent in WordPress’ dominance? What’s changed? And how far can we take this?

Today’s static website tools play into a totally different ecosystem than their predecessors. Many of the constraints that made dynamic websites the best option for creating anything but the most basic online brochure have fallen away. 

### THE BROWSER IS GROWING UP

When Tim Berners-Lee launched the first website of the World Wide Web, a browser was a simple document viewer that could display hypertext, links and little else.

Today, we’re finally in the process of burying the last browser that has been holding the web back (RIP Internet Explorer 8). The modern browser is an operating system in its own right, no longer merely displaying documents downloaded from the web, but capable of running full-fledged web applications, making external calls to API, storing data locally, opening WebSockets to streaming servers, and even handling peer-to-peer connections to other browsers via WebRTC.

With the maturation of browsers, many features that used to require dynamic code running on a server can be moved entirely to the client. Want comments on your website? Add Disqus, Isso or Facebook comments. Want social integration? Add Twitter or Facebook’s JavaScript widget to your website. Want real-time data updating live on your website? Add a squirt of Firebase. Want search? Add Swiftype. Want to add live chat support? Slaaks is there. 

The list goes on and on, as a whole ecosystem of purely browser-based add-ons to websites is emerging.

### THE CDN IS GOING MAINSTREAM

When Akamai launched the first content delivery network in 1999, only the largest web properties in the world could afford to deliver their web assets from CDN edge nodes distributed all over the world. It wasn’t that long ago that CDNs were used only by companies at the scale of CNN and Facebook, rather than mere mortals.

While Akamai still has enterprise-level pricing, today anyone can sign up for Amazon AWS and put CloudFront on top of their website. Also, companies like Fastly, MaxCDN and CloudFlare offer CDN services at prices that even a small business can afford.

A static website can be readily deployed directly to a CDN and served straight from local caches near end users. Fiddling with the configuration still takes some time, and cache invalidation can be tricky, but it’s doable and can be completely automated with services such as ours

### PERFORMANCE IS A MUST

The explosion of mobile devices has changed the face of the web in many ways. More and more visitors are coming to the web from a mobile device, sometimes on a 3G connection. Never has performance been as important as it is now.

We all know this data: 57% of online visitors will abandon a page if it takes longer than 3 seconds to load. People used to be willing to wait up to 10 seconds, but expectations are way higher today. And on mobile, where there’s no multi-tasking and little else to do, waiting for a website to load is so frustrating that more than 4% of people report that they’ve physically thrown their phone while using a slow mobile website!

No matter how much you optimize a dynamic website for performance or how many thousand of dollars you throw at it, it will never give you the same basic performance guarantee as a well-tuned static website hosted right on a CDN for a few bucks a month. With performance constantly growing in importance, it’s no wonder that developers are looking for ways to pre-generate their HTML, instead of letting the server spend time and resources on generating a page for every single HTTP request.

Static website generation also eliminates a lot of performance concerns during the development process.

If you’re building a dynamic database-driven website, the efficiency of the database queries you’re making is extremely important because they’ll need to be fast enough to run once for every single HTTP request. Even if a solid caching layer lies on top of your website, there’s often a risk that some requests will effectively work as cache-busters, triggering worst-case queries in the back end and causing the whole system to grind to a halt.

With a static-generated website, it doesn’t matter much if pulling content into a template takes a few seconds more or less: That only happens when you publish, and there will never be a performance penalty for end users.

### The Final piece of the Puzzle

The final piece of the puzzle, however, is content editing. While working directly in Markdown in a text editor and pushing to GitHub is close to the ideal workflow for a front-end developer, it’s not something you’d get normal, non-technical end user to participate in. 

Systems such as Contentful, Prismic.io and GatherContent decouple the CMS layer from the actual website builder. This makes them really interesting tools for multi-channel content management, where you’re writing content not just for a particular website, but also for a mobile app, a Facebook page or a white paper. Publishing new content triggers a webhook in a build system; then, a static website generator runs the build and fetches data from the content API; and the result is pushed straight to a CDN.

The ultimate answer is an open-source Static CMS system without any lock-in to a particular static website generator, Git host or hosting platform. It will be a great way to push the limit of what kind of website you can build with modern static website technology.]]></description><link>https://webfactories.biz/posts/who-needs-a-wordpress-site</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://webfactories.biz/posts/who-needs-a-wordpress-site</guid><category><![CDATA[recent-blog]]></category><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://webfactories.biz/img/uploads/who-needs-a-wordpress-site.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[What to do and what to spend on Digital Marketing]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src='https://webfactories.biz/img/uploads/digital-marketing-image.jpg' class='img-responsive'>

### Our recommendations based on the Five Gartner findings.

<ul class="circle-list"><li>Make a dramatic shift in your marketing budget allocation from offline to online marketing and use the 2.5% as a good average benchmark. That will result in a budget of $25,000 for each $1M of revenue. Take some risks here.</li><li>Ensure that your external partners have the marketing chops to adapt to the evolving landscape. Marketing has always been an art and a science, but the growth in underlying technology requires business owners to have access to technology talent.</li><li>Align your organizational goals of attracting, acquiring and retaining customers across the many digital channels with current and future technology landscape.</li><li>Take any savings from your offline marketing activities straight in to digital marketing activities, reinvest those funds into more of what's working well.</li><li>Take a fresh look at your corporate website and online advertising activities such as search engine marketing — don't let either run on autopilot. Both require significant investments in content creation, management and technology. Both were cited as the most important digital marketing activity to marketing's success.</li><li>Create social media awareness of your competencies, products and services. Second most important investment in the digital marketing mix.</li><li>Test how and what offerings can be sold via your company's E-commerce experience and determine how you'll drive buyers there.</li><li>Rely on agencies and other marketing service providers when you lack specialized expertise such as mobile web development .</li></ul>]]></description><link>https://webfactories.biz/posts/what-to-do-and-what-to-spend-on-digital-marketing</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://webfactories.biz/posts/what-to-do-and-what-to-spend-on-digital-marketing</guid><category><![CDATA[recent-blog]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://webfactories.biz/img/uploads/digital-marketing-image.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[What is the cost of a responsive web design]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src='https://webfactories.biz/img/uploads/cost-of-a-responsive-web2.jpg' class='img-responsive'>

If the term “responsive web design” is new to you, don’t feel bad, I promise you’re in the majority. In about 20 seconds you’ll know what it is and be able to look smart by talking about responsive design at dinner parties. The Responsive web design is simply this–a website design that adjusts gracefully to fit on a desktop, tablet, and smartphone browsers. Ever pull up a website on your smartphone and it was just a very tiny version of what you would see on your desktop, so you zoomed way in, and then moved the website around and enlarged and shrunk it as needed to read text and click on things? That was not a responsive website. Or if it was, it left out the key point of adjusting “gracefully.” A responsive website looks good no matter whether you’re looking at it on a smartphone, tablet, or desktop.

Considering that 2013 was first proclaimed as the year of the responsive web designs, you might wonder if you’re too late. No, you’re not, because in all likelihood all your competitors are late to the game as well. 2013 turned out to be the year when cutting edge companies in online marketing and web design got their acts together when it comes to responsive design. Businesses lag behind the cutting edge by at least a year when it comes to such things, and smaller businesses lagging almost two years behind the cutting edge. You've been safe for the time being, but now your competitors are figuring things out.

### Why Does It Matter?

Because it’s better, cleaner and cooler and very soon some of your competitors will jump on the band wagon.

To illustrate why responsiveness is better, I've taken the stats from an anonymous website that is widely representative of many others. If you use a tool like Google Analytics on your website you can look at these same stats and gauge how urgent the matter is for your company.

### Mobile vs. Desktop.

<p class="text-center"><img src="/img/uploads/responsive1.png" style="max-width:100%;"></p>

This pie chart on the right shows the percentages for visitors coming using mobile, tablet, and desktop devices for the past 12 months. You can view this pie chart for your own website by first selecting the past 12 months for your date range, and then on the left navigating to Audience &gt; Mobile &gt; Overview in Google Analytic. On the lower right you’ll see a small pie chart button. Push that, and you’ll see a chart like this one.

In this case the website receives almost 40% of its traffic from mobile devices. Given that this website is not responsive, nor has a mobile version, that’s a hefty chunk of visitors who are receiving a sub-optimal experience. 

### What does it cost and is it more expensive then a non-responsive design?

In theory, it is more expensive than a non-responsive design. Reasons being that it takes more planning to do a responsive design, that certain design elements need to be adapted for multiple views and that testing the site takes longer as it has to be viewed on multiple hardware devices. And unless you have done a redesign in the last year chances are that you will need a complete overhaul of your design.

In order to contain your budget, look for companies that are specialized in responsive web designs, that have overhauled a big chunk of their customers already, or are in the process of doing so and are prepared to work for a fixed monthly or yearly budget. Start with porting your current content to the new design and figure out later what new and appealing content you can add to your redesign. That will save you a lot of time in planning, as the job will be limited to do a new design and porting your existing content to the new design.

Use a **[Content Management System](http://www.webriq.us/)** that is expandable and where you can add content easily yourselves or have someone doing it for you at a fixed monthly cost.

Budget wise you are looking at around $3,000 for a complete overhaul to a responsive design. If you are more constrained in the budget, consider doing an overhaul for your home page only for starters and do the rest of the content at a later stage. That will take out roughly half of the cost of your responsive website. 

No matter how small or big your business is, if you are counting on your website to give you new leads and new business, jump to the responsive web design right now. Ask yourselves the hard question, can I afford to not do it, and should I cut some of my traditional ways of marketing my business and spent time and energy on getting visibility and credibility on the Internet instead.]]></description><link>https://webfactories.biz/posts/what-is-the-cost-of-a-responsive-web-design</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://webfactories.biz/posts/what-is-the-cost-of-a-responsive-web-design</guid><category><![CDATA[recent]]></category><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://webfactories.biz/img/uploads/cost-of-a-responsive-web2.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Website Trends for 2016]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src='https://webfactories.biz/img/uploads/website-trends-2016.jpg' class='img-responsive'>

### Trend 1: Unique Way of Using the Grid

Curious Space’s website is a great example of adding a pinch of organic freedom to an ordered grid layout.

You’ll quickly notice the photos of this website stacked on top of each other. Stacking them isn’t a problem, as when a user rolls over on an image, the Z-index of the selected image shifts, so it is pushed to the top of the pile of photos.

Upon scroll, the haphazard arrangement of their logo falls into place to spell out their company name.

<img src="/img/uploads/trends-2016-1.gif" width="100%">

### Trend 2: Custom-Drawn Illustrations

We’ve all thought it - “Why should I draw another [name of object] icon, when I can just grab it off an already existing vector pack from the web?” This line of thinking does save time and budget constraints, but how about integrating custom-made illustrations, or other artwork into the project budget in the first place?

Sites like Creative Freedom Guide, For Better Coffee, 2015 DConstruct Conference, or Ice & Sky all integrate custom-made / hand-drawn illustration work that greatly aid in telling their story and leaving a memorable experience for their users.

<img src="/img/uploads/trends-2016-2.gif" width="100%">

### Trend 3: Cinemagraphs

Did that picture just….move? We love cinemagraphs because like videos and photography, it enhances the desired mood for a website and gives it an additional layer of wonder, mystique, and elegance. Unlike videos, it won’t eat as much bandwidth, and unlike photos, it provides “something more” than a simple still shot. This technology has been around for a while already , and we hope to see it integrated into more websites in the future.

Examples from cinemegraphs can be found here.

### Trend 4: Semi-flat design

Flat design has slowly morphed over the past few years to semi-flat design. After Windows launched its Metro style, the design world became inundated with this trend. Unfortunately, this style did come with its usability pitfalls. This trend has slowly morphed into semi-flat design, largely in part due to both Android’s and Apple’s releases using this type of style. By integrating depth and dimension through the use of subtle shadows, card / tile concepts, and well-thought out transitions to help guide and orient users, semi-flat design aims to eliminate the problems that flat design had created.

<img src="/img/uploads/img8.jpg" width="100%">

### Trend 5 : Responsive Web Design

Let’s face it, after the implementation of RWD, there was no turning back. There will only be more devices sold on the market, so embracing and integrating responsive practices on websites will make the web sphere a better place for all.

<img src="/img/uploads/img9.jpg" width="100%">

### Trend 6 : Lazy Loading

On websites that feed content continuously, Lazy Loading aids in viewing immediate website content without waiting for the entire page to load. This is especially helpful for websites that are highly visual, such as Facebook, Instagram, or Pinterest. In a society where information is constantly being fed into our lives, lazy loading helps to simplify viewing of said content by loading only small chunks at a time.

<img src="/img/uploads/trends-2016-6.gif" width="100%">]]></description><link>https://webfactories.biz/posts/website-trends-for-2016</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://webfactories.biz/posts/website-trends-for-2016</guid><category><![CDATA[recent-blog]]></category><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://webfactories.biz/img/uploads/website-trends-2016.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/></item></channel></rss>